

SIDDHARTH GARG

Developer, Al Engineer, Computer Science Pre Final Year Student

- @ i@siddharthgarg.in
- www.siddharthgarg.in
- Agra, India
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sidg510/
- https://github.com/realsidg/

EDUCATION

Btech, Computer Science | VIT Vellore (Institute of Eminence)

- **1** 07 2018 Present
- Vellore, India
- CGPA: 8.93

12th Grade, All India Senior School Certificate Examination(AISSCE) | Delhi Public School, RK Puram

- ****** 07 2015 05 2017
- New Delhi, India
- Score: 90%

10th Grade, All India Secondary School Certificate (AISSC) | Delhi Public School, Agra

- 2015
- New Delhi, India
- CGPA: 9.4

TECH STACK

Programming

Python C++ C Java JavaScript SQL

AI/ML

Image Recognition CNNs Sentiment Analysis

RNNs Topic Modeling Object Detection

Web Development

Django Flask NodeJS PHP ReactJS

UI/UX

 Illustrator
 Canva
 Adobe XD
 Photoshop

ACHIEVEMENTS

by ACM, VIT

Consecutive First Prize, RCPC 2020 and 2019 Coding Competition, involving severalrounds

Runner Up, Hackathon by VIT
Hello World 2.0 hack conducted by Vinnovate

Winner, Jumble Ladder 2018
Competive Coding at Gravitas 2018 ny IEEEVIT

DBMS Hackathon, VIT 2019, 3rd Position
Database Management and Systems
hackathon conducted by VIT

ABOUT ME

Passionate developer, inquisitive, fast learner with experience in Full Stack Web Development and a specialist in Artificial Intelligence and Data Science. Well equippe with advanced level python, C++. Experience in creating end to end pipelines for data science projects. Deployed models on REST API, Object Detection on Raspberry Pi. IBM's Professional Certification in AI, Specialization in Deep Learning.

EXPERIENCE

Computer Vision Engineer | FindMind Analytics

Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

Programmed a high accuracy end to end pipeline with a REST API for OCR and masking of clients' sensitive documents using object detection, increasing speed 30x and accuracy to 97% from 60%

Deep Learning Intern | The Symbionic Company

May 2020 - Sep 2020

Produced a Dataset and Developed a deeplearning based object detection model for recognizing different grip patterns, to be fed into a 3D prosthetic robotic hand.

Marketing Head, Vellore Executive Board & Volunteer | ERIDE (NGO)

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Vellore, India

Empowering Rural India with Digital Education(ERIDE) aims on delivering digital literacy tounderprivileged people. Joined as a freshman, from teaching kids in orphanages, community centres to leading the NGO as a board member

Creative Head | Mozilla Firefox Club VIT

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020

▼ Vellore, India

Oversaw the club's activities, mentored designers, guided junior members in technical projects.

Senior Core Committee Member, Tech | Computer Society of India, VIT

Dec 2018 - Dec 2019

▼ Vellore, India

Organized hackathons, lead workshops and programmed CTFs, with amazingly talentedpeople I was fortunate enough to work with themon projects exposing students to new concepts.

PROJECTS

Malware Family classification using Convolutional Neural Networks on Byte Sequences |

GUI based End to End Auto ML dashboard for object detection and masking. | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

REST API for OCR and masking of sensitive data in Identity documents using image processing and object detection | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

Sentiment Analysis and Topic Modelling of primetime News-hourDebates from different news channels

TB Saathi (Tuberculosis Diagnosis using neural networks tool) | # | 2nd Prize in Hello World Hack

Minesweeper construction & solving algorithm | 🜎 | 🏶

Customer Segmentation using RFM technique | 😱